aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
Ashura and Indra
((アシュラ : ムムム…。
Elder Brother! How can you
read all that stuff?!
And Father too...
Why does he write so much?
だぁ～！
It all has to do with Ninshu.
兄さん
なんで そんなに読めるんだよ。
Every word means something.
父さんも
なんで こんなに書くかな…。
I know that, but...
(インドラ)全部 忍宗に関することだ。
すべてが役に立つ。
それは わかってるけど…。
That's not it...
Like this, maybe?
The two studied together,
and played together.
This one's huge!
(違うな… こうかな…))
Ashura! The net!
Get me the net!
Be careful.
(ハゴロモ)２人は
ともに学び ともに遊んだ。
Go slow and steady!
Gotcha!
((こいつは でかいぞ！
アシュラ タモだ タモ。
Ashura!
あぁ…。
気をつけろ 慎重にいけよ。
えいっ！
Look!
アシュラ！
I got it, Elder Brother!
Damn it. You're so impulsive.
You got a bite too!
見て！ やったよ 兄さん！
You're right!
まったく 無茶なやつだ。
It might be bigger than yours!
お前の竿にも きてるぞ。
ほんとだ！
兄さんのより大きいかも。
Oh, it's just driftwood.
(アシュラ)なんだ 木か…。
Whoa!
Amazing! It's a huge fish!
Nice one, Ashura!
Yeah!
But Elder Brother,
わぁ！ すごい おっきな魚だ。
what did you just do?
よかったな アシュラ。
うん。
At the time,
Ninshu did not have a practical
application for fighting yet.
(でも兄さん… 今 何をしたの？))
My original intent for it was
to help bring souls together.
Healthy bodies to sustain
wholesome spirits...
(ハゴロモ)その頃の忍宗は→
まだ武術的要素は
持っていなかった。
I didn't feel any need...
for any martial arts
that went beyond that.
そもそも わしの望みは心の絆だ。
健全な精神を宿すための
健全な肉体。
But due to Indra's innovations,
それを鍛える以上の
武術の必要性を→
the course of Ninshu
was drastically changed.
感じてはいなかった。
- Wow!
だが インドラの発明により→
W-What did you just do, Elder Brother?!
忍宗の流れは
大きく変わることになった。
When infusing chakra to release power,
I noticed that the formation of
your hands make a difference.
((あっ！
(弟子たち)おぉ！
な… 何をやったの？ 兄さん。
I think you can use various powers
by the way you shape
and combine your fingers.
チャクラを練り
力を発動させるためには→
Really?
手を結ぶ型が関係してることに
気づいたんだ。
So I'm calling the formation
of your hands "sign"
and the manifestation
of the power "jutsu."
型の組み合わせしだいでは→
Sign and jutsu...
いろんな力が
使えるようになると思う。
That's amazing, Elder Brother!
そうなの？
うん。
手の型を印 発動する現象を術って
名づけてみた。
I inherited powers from
my mother, Kaguya.
印と術…。
So I don't have to weave
signs to invoke jutsu.
(すごい！ すごいよ兄さん！))
But this was not the case
for my pupils
(ハゴロモ)母 カグヤの力を継いだ
わしには→
with whom
I shared my chakra.
When Indra was
merely ten years old,
術を使うのに印を結ぶ必要はない。
he was inventing jutsu
that even I could not do.
He was one who was worthy
だが チャクラを分け与えた者たちは
そうではなかった。
of being called
the "Genius of Ninshu."
インドラは わずか10歳にして→
わしにもできぬ発明をしてのけた。
まさに忍宗の天才と呼ぶに
ふさわしかった。
The invention of jutsu using signs
changed the foundation
of people's lives.
It became such that anyone
who trained hard
would be able to use jutsu.
(ハゴロモ)印による 術の発明は
人々の生活を根本的に変えた。
But I was a foolish father.
修業を積んだ者なら 誰にでも→
I did not notice that
the powers of darkness
術を使うことが
できるようになったのだ。
that were targeting Indra
were already on the move...
だが わしは愚かな父であった。
気づいてやることが
できなかったのだ。
すでに この頃から インドラを狙う
闇の力が うごめいていたことに。
Ashura!
Are you okay?
Ouch...
I'm okay, Elder Brother.
When releasing chakra,
you must be extremely careful.
Or you can be seriously hurt.
((うわっ！
アシュラ！
We possess more chakra
than other people.
大丈夫か？
イテテ…。
大丈夫だよ 兄さん。
Sorry.
チャクラを扱うときは
細心の注意を払え。
でないと 大ケガするぞ。
俺たちは
他の人より チャクラが多いんだ。
Your invention has transformed
Ninshu greatly.
(アシュラ)ごめん…。
Yes...
But I don't know if
that was a good thing.
Why is that?
(ハゴロモ)お前の発明が
忍宗を大きく変えたな。
Training used to be more spiritual.
Now it's become focused
on honing the jutsu itself.
はい…。 ですが これで
よかったのかは わかりません。
In time, it could be used
as a weapon
and create chaos in the world.
(ハゴロモ)なぜだ？
これまで 精神的だった修業は→
Your astuteness is
almost frightening, my son.
術を中心にした修業へと
移ってしまいました。
I didn't realize you had thought
so deeply about it.
それは いずれ 武器となり→
Yes...
この世界に
戦乱をもたらすかもしれません。
But what will be will be.
No one can stop the flow of time.
(ハゴロモ)恐るべき息子よ…。
Had you not invented signs,
someone else would have.
そこまで 思いを
めぐらせていたか。
はい…。
If chakra is to become a weapon,
(ハゴロモ)だが それで いいのだ。
then we must train the soul
even harder to control that chakra.
時の歩みは
誰にも止めることはできぬ。
印は お前が発明しなくとも
いずれ 誰かが発明した。
Yes...
チャクラが武器となるなら→
それを制御するための
更なる心の修業を積めばよいのだ。
(インドラ)はい…。
So it was you...
You inherited Mother's powers!
Who's there?!
Come out!
I'll always be watching you.
キミのほうだったんだ。
母上の力を受け継いだのは…。
誰だ!? 出て来い！
僕は いつも キミを見ているよ。
Very impressive, Master Indra!
Next up, Master Ashura!
Right!
(フタミ)見事ですな インドラ様！
次！ アシュラ様。
おう！
Stop there!
Are you okay, Ashura?
Yeah.
You're really strong, Elder Brother.
うわっ！
Training's over!
(フタミ)そこまで！
I'm going to play with Taizo
and the others!
大丈夫か？ アシュラ。
うん… やっぱり 兄さんは強いな。
Good grief...
Father, I'm going to go train
a little more on the hill in the back.
修業 終わりだ！
俺 タイゾウたちと遊んでくる!!
(フタミ)まったく…。
父上… 私は 裏山で
もう少し 修業してきます。
It seems Master Indra has
assumed great command
of the powers
you passed on to him.
And that's a good thing.
Why is that?
Well, if you're to name
a successor one day,
(フタミ)ふむ…
どうやら ハゴロモ様の力は→
見事 インドラ様に
引き継がれたようですな。
it's customary to select
the first son.
Having a younger son inherit
could sow the seeds of discontent.
ですが それで よかった。
なぜだ？
(フタミ)それは やはり
いつか 後継者を決めるなら→
No one would object
to Master Indra,
him being the one
naturally gifted with Ninshu.
長男が継ぐのが 世間のならわし。
The future of Ninshu
is now secure.
もし 弟が継ぐとなれば
揉めごとの種ですからな。
インドラ様の忍宗の才能なら
誰も 文句を言いますまい。
Hey!
You're late, Ashura!
これで 忍宗は安泰ですな。
Sorry, sorry!
I'll have you know that I came
as soon as I finished with training.
ふむ…。
Anyway, what's up?
(アシュラ)お～い！
Look at this!
(タイゾウ)遅いぞ アシュラ！
(アシュラ)悪い 悪い！
What is this?
Wild boar tracks.
これでも 修業が終わって
すぐに来たんだぜ。
A lot of the fields have
been damaged recently.
何か あったのか？
(ガスカ)これ 見てよ！
That's not good.
Why don't we go
and hunt it down?
(アシュラ)なんだ？ これ…。
(エダシ)イノシシの足跡だよ。
But isn't that dangerous?
(エダシ)最近 あちこちの畑を
荒らしてるんだって。
We should be fine!
へぇ… それは迷惑だな。
If worse comes to worst,
we've got Ashura.
(タイゾウ)なぁ みんなで
退治しにいかねえか？
You can use your Ninshu
to bring it down!
(アシュラたち)えっ!?
What?!
- That's right!
- So let's go!
でも 危ないだろ そんなの。
(タイゾウ)大丈夫じゃねえ？
いざとなったら
アシュラがいるじゃねえか。
お前の忍宗で やっつけようぜ！
え～っ!?
そっか！
なら 行こうぜ。
う… うん…。
Are you there?!
I'm so happy that
you sensed my presence!
そこか！
It's a child...
嬉しいよ。
僕を感じてくれてるんだね。
What do you want?
Why do you keep following me?
You will grow strong.
You have the desire, potential,
and talent for Ninshu.
子供…。
However...
(インドラ)何の用だ？
なぜ 私をつけ回す!?
You're still not aware
of your true power.
キミは強くなる。
忍宗への向上心も 才能もある。
My "true power"?
An even greater power
lies dormant inside you.
でも まだ 本当の自分の力には
気づいていない。
But there is one condition
for awakening that power.
自分の力？
Who are you?
キミには もっと すごい力が
眠ってるってことさ。
How do you know that?
It doesn't matter.
でも その力を目覚めさせるには
条件があるけどね フフフ。
If you awaken your power,
お前は何者なんだ？
my wish will come true one day...
どうして
そんなことがわかるんだ？
そんなこと
どうだっていいじゃない。
Well, never mind about that.
キミの力が目覚めてくれれば…。
We were talking about awakening
your power, weren't we?
いつか 僕の望みも叶う。
Do you want to know how?
It has nothing to do
with training, you know.
まあ そんな話はいいや。
キミの力を
目覚めさせる話だったね。
You must lose love...
知りたい？
What do you mean?
Like having a person you love, die.
それは
修業なんかじゃないんだよね。
愛を失うこと。
Let's test it out!
どういう意味だ？
例えば
キミの愛する人間が死ぬ とか…。
What are you going to do?
Wait!
試してみようよ。
Ashura!
何をするつもりだ？
待て！
Over here!
The tracks continue over here!
(アシュラ！))
Hey...
((こっちだ
こっちに続いてるぞ。
Don't tell me...
- There it is!
- Run!
It's coming this way!
おい まさか。
All right! I'll use that...
(ガスカ)出た！
(エダシ)逃げろ！
うわ～ こっちに来た！
よし あれを使って。
What's with him anyway?!
うわ～！
That's no ordinary boar.
なんだ こいつ…。
《こいつ 普通のイノシシじゃない》
Ashura! Use Ninshu!
Um... um...
うわっ。
Watch out, Ashura!
Run away!
アシュラ 忍宗を使え。
えっと えっと…。
Shiro!
(ガスカ)危ない アシュラ。
(エダシ)逃げて！
ワン ワン！
シロ！
Ashura!
Elder Brother...
Hurry, go!
How dare you do this
to my younger brother!
(インドラ)アシュラ。
兄さん…。
早く行け。
貴様 よくも弟を！
Elder Brother!
Are you all right?
Yeah...
But Shiro's...
兄さん。
Shiro gave his life to protect you.
大丈夫か？
うん。
Give him a proper burial.
でも シロが…。
Okay...
シロは 命がけで
お前を守ったんだ。
Brother, your eyes!
手厚く葬ってやれ。
うん…。
This is...
兄さん その目。
Elder Brother?
これは…。
I know you're there!
兄さん？
What did you do?!
Oh nothing.
That's your true power.
From now on, you'll use
those eyes to see the truth.
いるのは わかっている
お前 何をした？
何も。
See you later!
それがキミの本当の力だよ。
これからキミは その目で
真実を見つめながら生きていく。
He's gone!
またね フフフフ。
消えたか。
Amazing!
Ouch!
Put everything you've got into it!
Y-Yes!
Ashura, you too!
うわ～。
You can't expect to use
Ninshu like that!
すげえ。 うっ…。
イテテ…。
Okay...
もっと気合いを入れろ。
はい…。
Sorry.
アシュラ お前もだ。
Ever since he awakened
his Sharingan,
そんなことでは
忍宗は使いこなせないぞ。
Master Indra's progress
has been phenomenal.
はい うん… ごめん。
He's disciplined and he has
the right temperament to guide others.
うんうん
写輪眼を開眼してから→
He can take over Ninshu anytime.
インドラ様の成長は
すばらしいですな。
規律を重んじ
指導者としての態度も→
堂に入ったものだ。
これなら いつでも
忍宗を継げる。
Master Indra is simply amazing.
When he glares at you with
those eyes, I can't even move.
He's so young,
and he's already an instructor.
Master Indra's the one who
invented hand signs and jutsu.
いや～ なんとも
インドラ様はすごいなあ！
But recently he's been too strict.
あの眼で睨まれると
動けなくなる。
Even earlier, he didn't go easy at all.
あの歳で師範だからな。
印だって術だって
インドラ様の発明だ。
If Master Indra becomes
the successor,
I don't know if I'd be
able to follow him.
しかし 正直
最近は厳しすぎる。
You're right.
Sometimes the way Master Indra
looks at us seems almost hateful.
さっきも まるで
手加減なしだからな。
インドラ様が二代目になったら
ついていけるかどうか…。
Master Ashura is much easier
to approach,
but he's not skilled at all.
確かに…
インドラ様の鋭い視線は→
Nothing ever goes perfectly, doesn't it?
I'll say.
我々を見下しているような
気もするしなあ。
アシュラ様のほうは
気さくに話せるが→
才能が
まるでないからなあ。
うまくいかんものだな。
本当だ。
Elder Brother!
Are you going to train
in the mountains again?
Yes, that's my intent.
Can I come with you?
I'm sorry...
兄さん
今日も裏山へ修業に？
I want to train alone.
With you, I...
ああ そのつもりだ。
Yeah, you're right.
We're too far apart in skill.
一緒に行っていいかな？
すまない。
一人で修業したいんだ
私とお前では…。
E-Elder Brother!
Hmm?
そ そうだよね
レベルが違いすぎるもんね。
I... I think you should ease up
on the others a bit
during practice...
兄さん。
うん？
When you're serious,
they end up getting hurt.
あの もう少し修業のとき→
You have a point.
I'll think about it.
手加減してやったほうが
いいと思うんだ。
他の人に兄さんが
本気でやったら→
みんな 怪我しちゃうし。
そうだな
考えておこう。
Come out, I know you're here.
Impressive...
It's been a while, hasn't it?
I'm not like before.
So it seems.
出て来い
いるのはわかってる。
Have you gotten used to those eyes?
さすが
久しぶりだね。
Don't glare at me like that.
もう前とは違う。
みたいだね。
I wish you'd show me
some gratitude at least.
Why should I be grateful to you?
もう その眼にも
慣れたかな？
Well...
I'm the one who awakened
those eyes.
そんなに睨まないでよ
少しは感謝してほしいな。
By the way...
Did you see something
with those eyes?
なぜお前に
感謝する必要がある？
Like the future of Ninshu?
Or your dreams?
だって その眼を開眼させたのは
僕なんだから。
You've already sensed it, right?
ところで その眼で
何か見えた？
That you're special.
That you have the power to
change the future of Ninshu.
忍宗の未来とか
自分の理想とか。
キミは もう気づいてるんだろ？
You have overwhelming power.
自分が特別だって。
自分には忍宗の未来を
変えられる力があるんだって。
You've inherited most
of Hagoromo's power.
Ashura can't hold a candle to you.
キミの力は圧倒的だもんね。
In time, your power will rival
that of your father, Hagoromo.
ハゴロモの力の多くは
キミが継いだ。
アシュラなどは
足もとにも及ばない。
No one will be able
to compete with you...
いずれ キミの力は
父親のハゴロモにも匹敵する。
Next!
誰も キミには敵わなくなる
フフフフ！
What's the matter?!
Isn't anyone willing to face me?
(インドラ)次！
どうした 誰も私の相手を
する者はいないのか？
Such cowards.
不甲斐ない。
Elder Brother!
Why?!
You said you'd think it over!
Ashura...
You don't have the Sharingan,
so you won't understand.
Power is what rules the world.
兄さん どうして？
考えてくれるって…。
Power maintains order.
アシュラ 写輪眼を持たぬ
お前にはわからん。
In time, I will take over Ninshu
and fulfill my dream.
世界を束ねていくのは力であり
力による規律だ。
Elder Brother...
いずれ私は忍宗を継ぎ
その理想を貫く。
(兄さん…))
kaze ga fui te iku
The wind is blowing
yoru o mata yorokete aruku
I stagger through the night
butsukatte koron de shippai bakkashite
Colliding, falling, and failing
make sou ni naru kedo
I'm always about to lose
warawaretatte ii yo kanarazu umaku iku sa
Go ahead and laugh, I'll figure out a way
gomen ne datte ieru
I'm even willing to say I'm sorry
nakitai nakitai nakitai kurai ni
Until we feel like crying and crying
kirei na tsuki no shita uta o utaou
Let's sing a song under the pretty moonlight
donna ni kuradanai sekai datte ii yo
It doesn't matter how awful the world is
setsunai setsunai rarabai kurai ni
Like a sad, sad lullaby
mune ga kurushikute mo hecchara na no sa
even if it hurts inside, it won't bother us
naki sou naki sou naki sou na hodo
Until we're about to cry and cry
yasashii uta datte arun dakara
There will always be a gentle song
Hey, did you hear?
It seems Master Hagoromo
is close to choosing
a successor for Ninshu!
It's between Masters Indra
and Ashura, eh?
I wonder who it's going to be?
It's plain as day!
It's the eldest, Master Indra,
who's got the outstanding natural gift
for Ninshu!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Tumultuous Journey"
From here on, I will decide
the successor for Ninshu.